<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Comrade</title>
    <link>http://coffeecomrade.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>bryanwarren@gmail.com (Bryan Matthew Warren)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-07-10T23:55:18+02:00</pubDate>
    <copyright>Copyright 2011</copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <description>Coffee reviews, tasting notes and commentary</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Pachamama - Santa Teresa, Peru</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Feb 23 00:00:00 +0100 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-pachamama-peru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This review is difficult to write. Difficult not only because I have to be harsh, but also because I feel like I&amp;#8217;ve failed. I attempt to find a redeeming or commendable quality in just about every brew I try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t find anything to like about &lt;a href='http://www.pachamama.coop/detail.cfm?id=3930[jsshaper]:'&gt;Pachamama&amp;#8217;s Peruvian offering&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s just bad coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It lacks aroma. The mouthfeel is indistinguishable from tepid water. The acidity is off the chart. Its flavor is simple and singular; but unfortunately that flavor is dirt. I&amp;#8217;m not exaggerating, it tastes like dirt. Or, more specifically, dirt-laden coffee bean skins (chaff).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My typical review process is to brew and drink several cups over a few days, making notes each time. When I sit down to write the review, I&amp;#8217;ll brew up another cup and go over my previous notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sitting here drinking my third cup of this monstrosity and my opinion hasn&amp;#8217;t changed. The nuance that usually reveals itself after repeated tastings is completely absent. I hate this bean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things I do for you people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/pachamama">pachamama</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/0-stars">0-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-sumatra-mandheling.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Jan 26 00:00:00 +0100 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-dynamite-roasting-sumatra-mandheling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.dynamiteroasting.com/'&gt;Dynamite Roasting&lt;/a&gt; cooks up beans in Black Mountain, NC. The organic roaster offers a wide variety of both blends and single-origin roasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling_-beans.jpg' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mandailing'&gt;Mandheling&lt;/a&gt; beans are a medium roast that edge slightly toward dark. The aroma is deep and decidedly &amp;#8220;brown&amp;#8221; with strong punches of salt and earth. Yeah, &amp;#8220;earth.&amp;#8221; In a good way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling/tasting_-dynamite_-sumatra-mandheling_-grounds.jpg[jsshaper]:' alt='Dynamite Roasting - Sumatra Mandheling - Grounds' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nut flavor is pervasive, held up by subtle wood and oil textures. There&amp;#8217;s a light hint of dark fruit–maybe cherry or pomegranate. The brew feels very thin and almost weightless. While this may seem like a reflection of poor body, the finished cup has an excellent build that allows the light weight to shine through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could drink this stuff all day. The aftertaste is just right; it doesn&amp;#8217;t overstay its welcome. Surprisingly, the cup smells precisely as delicious as the grounds. This almost never happens. It&amp;#8217;s an honest roast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='verdict'&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamite Roasting&amp;#8217;s &lt;strong&gt;Sumatra Mandheling&lt;/strong&gt; is a real workhorse. It&amp;#8217;s a general-purpose roast that works just as well in a drip pot as in espresso drinks. Several local joints keep this in their air pots. It&amp;#8217;s good that way, but loses a lot of complexity. Brewed any other way, this roast is exceedingly excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My review may not have reflected this, but I&amp;#8217;m trying to show a bit of restraint. Dynamite&amp;#8217;s Indonesian offering is my favorite coffee. No hyperbole. 5 Stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dynamite">dynamite</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/medium-roast">medium-roast</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/5-stars">5-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasting Notes - Equal Exchange's Organic Midnight Sun</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat Jan 22 00:00:00 +0100 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/tasting-notes-equal-exchange-organic-midnight-sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I Grabbed this &lt;a href='http://shop.equalexchange.com/ProductInfo.aspx?productid=10032'&gt;dark roast from Equal Exchange&lt;/a&gt; at the local co-op on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-beans.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Beans' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how oily these suckers are! They&amp;#8217;re practically dripping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brewed in my small Chemex, the finished product was decent, but lacking; so I moved on to the AeroPress. Using two tablespoons of beans–finely ground–produced a very tasty cup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-crema.jpg' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Crema' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aroma is thick with syrup, almost malty. The flavor is quite rich with absolutely no notes of fruit and a very heavy, bold coffee flavor. Its taste is rather simple. It feels heavy in the mouth with very low acidity. The crema is creamy and rich with oil. As I often experience–quite enjoyably–with dark roasts there is a subtle coconut aftertaste mixed with dark chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Midnight Sun is drinkable despite its fairly modest complexity. It lingers on the tongue &lt;em&gt;slighty&lt;/em&gt; too long and tastes exclusively of coffee. The flavor lacks nuance, as is common with the darkest roasts, but this is disappointing only if you&amp;#8217;re expecting a diverse flavor profile. This roast won&amp;#8217;t grab everyone, but those who enjoy their drink bold will find something to like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://coffeecomrade.com/photos/tasting_-equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun/equal-exchange_-organic-midnight-sun_-cup.jpg[jsshaper]:' alt='Equal Exchange - Organic Midnight Sun - Finished Cup' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='verdict'&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; like dark roasts. 2 Stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/review">review</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/tasting-notes">tasting-notes</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/equal-exchange">equal-exchange</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/dark-roast">dark-roast</category>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/2-stars">2-stars</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brushing a Duck's Teeth</title>
      <link>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Jan 18 00:00:00 +0100 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://coffeecomrade.com/articles/brushing-a-ducks-teeth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always been lousy at introductions, so I&amp;#8217;ll get straight to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, coffee and I – we sort of have a &amp;#8216;thing.&amp;#8217; I confess. Well, it&amp;#8217;s really more of a lusty infatuation. I figure if we&amp;#8217;re going to keep spending this much time together, I should probably learn a thing or two about her. You know, so we have something to talk about &lt;em&gt;above&lt;/em&gt; the sheets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll use this space to collect tasting notes and make snarky comments on the generally snobby coffee community. I won&amp;#8217;t, however, get into pedantic discussions over the precise pressure to pull a proper shot of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I probably will keep up the alliteration.&lt;span&gt;jsshaper&lt;/span&gt;: http://jsshaper.org &amp;#8220;an extensible framework for JavaScript syntax tree shaping&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://coffeecomrade.com/tag/introduction">introduction</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>